Daniel C. Dennett Papers MS138
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Writings, 1958 -- 2015; MS138.001; 4.15 Linear Feet; 415 Digital Object(s)
  - Quining Qualia, 1988 -- 2006; MS138.001.001.00103; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Qualia eliminieren [German translation of Quining Qualia], 2006; MS138.001.001.00103.00006; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Précis of The Intentional Stance [and] Science, Philosophy, and Interpretation ], 1988; MS138.001.001.00104; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Précis of The Intentional Stance [and] Science, Philosophy, and Interpretation, 1988; MS138.001.001.00104.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
    - Précis of The Intentional Stance, 1988; MS138.001.001.00104.00002; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Science, Philosophy, and Interpretation, 1988; MS138.001.001.00104.00003; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - The Intentional Stance in Theory and Practice, 1988; MS138.001.001.00105; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 1)
  - Why Everyone is a Novelist, 1988 -- 2003; MS138.001.002.00001; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Why Everyone is a Novelist, 1988; MS138.001.002.00001.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    - Пoчemy КaждЬiй Из Нac Являeтcя Нoвeллиcтoм [Russian translation of Why Everyone is a Novelist], 2003; MS138.001.002.00001.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Review of Psychosemantics, by Jerry Fodor, 1988-07; MS138.001.002.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Cognitive science; Fodor, Jerry A.
  - Coming to Terms with the Determined: A Review of A Theory of Determinism: The Mind, Neuroscience, and Life-Hopes, by Ted Honderich, 1988; MS138.001.002.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Why Creative Intelligence is Hard to Find, 1988; MS138.001.002.00004; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Review of The Disappearance of Introspection, by William Lyons, 1988; MS138.001.002.00005; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Introspection; Conciousness; Perception; Lyons, William
  - Dialogue, 1988; MS138.001.002.00006; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Intentionality, 1988; MS138.001.002.00007; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Evolution, Error and Intentionality, 1988; MS138.001.002.00008; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Speaking for Our Selves: An Assessment of Multiple Personality Disorder, 1989 -- 1991; MS138.001.002.00009; Dennett, Daniel C.; Humphery, Nicholas
    - Speaking for Our Selves: An Assessment of Multiple Personality Disorder, 1989; MS138.001.002.00009.00001; Dennett, Daniel C.; Humphery, Nicholas (Box 2)
    - Speaking for Our Selves: An Assessment of Multiple Personality Disorder, 1991; MS138.001.002.00009.00002; Dennett, Daniel C.; Humphery, Nicholas (Box 2)
  - Murmurs in the Cathedral: A Review of The Emperor's New Mind, by Roger Penrose, 1989; MS138.001.002.00010; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Conciousness; Physics- Philosophy; Artificial intelligence; Thought and Thinking; Penrose, Roger
  - Cognitive Ethology: Hunting for Bargains or a Wild Goose Chase?, 1989 -- 2001; MS138.001.002.00011; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Cognitive Ethology: Hunting for Bargains or a Wild Goose Chase?, 1989; MS138.001.002.00011.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    - L'etologia cognitiva: un buon affare o tempo sprecato? [Italian translation of Cognitive Ethology: Hunting for Bargains or a Wild Goose Chase?], 2001; MS138.001.002.00011.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - The Origins of Selves, 1989; MS138.001.002.00012; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Self-preservation; Self-organization; Multiple-personality disorder; Conciousness
  - Review of Darwin and the Emergence of Evolutionary Theories of Mind and Behavior, by Robert Richards, 1989; MS138.001.002.00013; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Teaching an Old Dog New Tricks, 1990; MS138.001.002.00014; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Thinking with a Computer, 1990; MS138.001.002.00015; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Distributed cognition; Artificial intelligence; LOGO (computer language)
  - The Evolution of Consciousness, 1990; MS138.001.002.00016; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - The Myth of Original Intentionality, 1990; MS138.001.002.00017; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - The Interpretation of Texts, People, and Other Artifacts, 1990; MS138.001.002.00018; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Memes and the Exploitation of Imagination, 1990; MS138.001.002.00019; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Memetics; Cognition; Natural selection; Self-replication
  - Artificial Life: A Feast for the Imagination: A Review of Artificial Life, edited by Christopher G. Langton, 1990; MS138.001.002.00020; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Artificial intelligence; Artificial life; Self-replication; Computer simulation
  - Dr. Pangloss Knows Best, 1990; MS138.001.002.00021; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Abstracting from Mechanism, 1990; MS138.001.002.00022; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Betting Your Life on an Algorithm, 1990; MS138.001.002.00023; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Demystifying Consciousness: An Interview with Daniel C. Dennett, 1990; MS138.001.002.00024; Dennett, Daniel C.; Brockman, John (Box 2)
  - Attitudes about ADHD: Some Analogies and Aspects, 1990; MS138.001.002.00025; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Consciousness Explained, 1991 -- 1998; MS138.001.002.00026; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - The Brain in the Vat, 1991 -- 1995; MS138.001.002.00026.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    - Consciousness Explained, 1998; MS138.001.002.00026.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Real Patterns, 1991 -- 2001; MS138.001.002.00027; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Real Patterns, 1991-01; MS138.001.002.00027.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
      Belief; Cognitive science; Intentional stance
    - Pautas Reales [Portuguese translation of Real Patterns], 1991; MS138.001.002.00027.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    - Patrones Reales [Spanish translation of Real Patterns], 2001; MS138.001.002.00027.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Mother Nature Versus the Walking Encyclopedia: A Western Drama, 1991; MS138.001.002.00028; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - A Gadfly's View, 1991; MS138.001.002.00029; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Granny's Campaign for Safe Science, 1991; MS138.001.002.00030; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Semantics; Intentionality; Teleosemantics; Fodor, Jerry A.
  - Lovely and Suspect Qualities: Commentary on The Independence of Consciousness and Sensory Quality, by David Rosenthal, 1991; MS138.001.002.00031; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Two Contrasts: Folk Craft Versus Folk Science, and Belief versus Opinion, 1991; MS138.001.002.00032; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - The Brain and its Boundaries: Review of The Problem of Consciousness, by Colin McGinn, 1991; MS138.001.002.00033; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Modelli del Cervello e il Punto di Vista dell'Osservatore, 1991; MS138.001.002.00034; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - A Dash to Solve the Puzzle of the Mind, 1991; MS138.001.002.00035; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Intentionality, 1991; MS138.001.002.00036; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Exploring the Space of the Turing Test: A First Step, 1991; MS138.001.002.00037; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Ways of Establishing Harmony, 1990 -- 1991; MS138.001.002.00038; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Ways of Establishing Harmony, 1991; MS138.001.002.00038.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
      Meaning (philosophy); Semantics; Natural selection; Intentionality; Intentional stance; Dretske, Fred I.
    - Ways of Establishing Harmony, 1990; MS138.001.002.00038.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Hitting the Nail on the Head, 1992; MS138.001.002.00039; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Color perception; Color (philosophy); Gibson, James Jerome
  - Temporal Anomalies of Consciousness: Implications of the Uncentered Brain, 1992; MS138.001.002.00040; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Commandos of the Word, 1992; MS138.001.002.00041; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Language; Animal intelligence; Cognitive closure
  - Do-It-Yourself Understanding, 1992 -- 2007; MS138.001.002.00042; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - La Compréhension Artisanale [French translation of Do-It-Yourself Understanding], 1992; MS138.001.002.00042.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
      This article was also published online at: http://ase.tufts.edu/cogstud/papers/doityour.htm and includes text from "Ways of Establishing Harmony."
      Meaning (philosophy); Content; Semantics; Mental representation; Dretske, Fred I.
    - Do-It-Yourself Understanding, 2007; MS138.001.002.00042.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Regissörer i medvetandets strömmar, 1992; MS138.001.002.00043; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Time and the Observer: The Where and When of Consciousness in the Brain (with commentaries), 1992; MS138.001.002.00044; Dennett, Daniel C.; Kinsbourne, Marcel (Box 2)
    Consciousness; Self; Time perception - philosophy; Subjectivity; Cartesian theater; Dualism; Consciousness (multiple drafts model)
  - Revolution on the Mind: Review of The Embodied Mind, by Francisco Varela, Evan Thompson and Eleanor Rosch [and] Bright Air, Brilliant Fire, by Gerald M. Edelman, 1992; MS138.001.002.00045; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Consciousness; Cognition; Embodied cognition; Artificial intelligence; Meditation
  - An Interview with Dan Dennett, 1992; MS138.001.002.00046; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Multiple Personality, 1992; MS138.001.002.00047; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - 'Filling In' Versus Finding Out: A Ubiquitous Confusion in Cognitive Science, 1992; MS138.001.002.00048; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Living on the Edge: A Reply to Seven Essays on Consciousness Explained, 1993; MS138.001.002.00049; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Nella mente c'é Marilyn, 1993; MS138.001.002.00050; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Review of The Embodied Mind, by Francisco Varela, Evan Thompson and Eleanor Rosch, 1993; MS138.001.002.00051; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Cognition; Research; Methodology; Distributed cognition; Cognitive science; Perception; Experimental learning
  - Eddies in the Stream of Consciousness, 1993; MS138.001.002.00052; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Evolution, Teleology, Intentionality, 1993; MS138.001.002.00053; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Learning and Labeling: Commentary on The Cognizer's Innards, A. Clark and A. Karmiloff-Smith, 1993; MS138.001.002.00054; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Connectionism; Language; Signs and symbols; Symbolism
  - Caveat Emptor, 1993; MS138.001.002.00055; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Consciousness; Phenomenology; Heterophenomenology; Cartesian theater; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Review of Unified Theories of Cognition, by Allen Newell, 1993; MS138.001.002.00056; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Cognitive science; Cognition; Artificial intelligence; Newell, Allen
  - Confusion Over Evolution: An Exchange, 1993; MS138.001.002.00057; Dennett, Daniel C.; Gould, Stephen Jay (Box 2)
    Evolutionary biology; Adaptationism; Natural selection; Gould, Stephen Jay
  - The Message Is: There Is No Medium, 1993; MS138.001.002.00058; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Back from the Drawing Board, 1993; MS138.001.002.00059; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Review of The Rediscovery of the Mind by John Searle, 1993; MS138.001.002.00060; Dennett, Daniel C.
    Consciousness; Functionalism; Intentionality; Searle, John R.
  - Down with School! Up with Logoland! Review of The Children's Machine: Rethinking School in the Age of the Computer, by Seymour Papert, 1993; MS138.001.002.00061; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    LOGO (computer language); LISP (computer language); Study and teaching (pedagogy); Education, Elementary
  - Artificial Life as Philosophy, 1994; MS138.001.002.00062; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Cognitive Science as Reverse Engineering: Several Meanings of 'Top-Down' and 'Bottom-Up', 1994; MS138.001.002.00063; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Cognitive science; Information Processing; Artificial intelligence; Artificial life
  - Counting Consciousnesses: None, One, Two or None of the Above?, 1994; MS138.001.002.00064; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Dennett and Carr Further Explained: An Exchange, 1994; MS138.001.002.00065; Dennett, Daniel C.; Carr, David (Box 2)
  - E Pluribus Unum?, 1994; MS138.001.002.00066; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Group Selection; Self; Sober, Elliot; Wilson, David Sloane
  - Get Real, 1994; MS138.001.002.00067; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Instead of Qualia, 1994; MS138.001.002.00068; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Real Consciousness, 1994; MS138.001.002.00069; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Il Se I Se. Quale Tipo di Realta? In forma di corrispondenza (Correspondence between Paolo Francesco Pieri and Daniel Dennett), 1994; MS138.001.002.00070; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Sifting the Evidence for Belief in the Past: Review of The Ancient Mind: Elements of Cognitive Archaeology, by Colin Renfrew and Ezra Zubrow, 1994; MS138.001.002.00071; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Ritual; Archaeology (Cognitive); Archaeology (Processual)
  - Self-Portrait, 1994; MS138.001.002.00072; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - The Practical Requirements for Making a Conscious Robot, 1994; MS138.001.002.00073; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Conciousness; Artificial intelligence; Phenomenology; Representation, Symbolic
  - Language and Intelligence, 1994 -- 1997; MS138.001.002.00074; Dennett, Daniel C.
    Alternative title: The Role of Language in Intelligence.
    - Language and Intelligence, 1994; MS138.001.002.00074.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
      Language; Animal intelligence; Cognitive closure; Memetics; Nature and nurture; Episodic memory
    - The Role of Language in Intelligence, 1997; MS138.001.002.00074.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
      This article was reprinted in Germany, but not translated into German.
  - Wired for Sound: Review of Patterns in the Mind, by Ray Jackendoff [and] The Language Instinct, by Steven Pinker, 1994; MS138.001.002.00075; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    This article was originally published in the London Review of Books (http://www.lrb.co.uk/). Permission has been granted to reproduce the piece on the Tufts Digital Library.
    Language; Pinker, Steven, 1954-; Jackendoff, Ray, 1945-; Chomsky, Noam
  - Darwin's Dangerous Idea: Evolution and the Meanings of Life, 1997 -- 2000; MS138.001.002.00076; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - L'idea pericolosa di Darwin: L'evoluzione e i significati della vita [Italian translation of Darwin's Dangerous Idea: Evolution and the Meanings of Life], 1997; MS138.001.002.00076.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
    - A Idea perigosa de Darwin evolucao e sentido da vida [Galician translation of Darwin's Dangerous Idea: Evolution and the Meanings of Life], 2000; MS138.001.002.00076.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
    - A Ideia perigosa de Darwin: Evolução e sentido da vida [Portugese translation of Darwin's Dangerous Idea: Evolution and the Meanings of Life], 2000; MS138.001.002.00076.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
  - Evolution as An Algorithm--The Ultimate Insult?, 1995; MS138.001.002.00077; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Comments nous tissons notre moi [French translation of How We Weave Ourselves], 1995; MS138.001.002.00078; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Interview with Daniel Dennett, 1995; MS138.001.002.00079; Dennett, Daniel C.; Unknown (Box 2)
  - In Defense of AI, 1995; MS138.001.002.00080; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Artificial intelligence; Connectionism; Intentionality; Dennett, Daniel C.; Searle, John R.; Dreyfus, Hubert L.
  - Darwin's Dangerous Idea (excerpted from the book), 1995 -- 1996; MS138.001.002.00081; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Darwin's Dangerous Idea (excerpted from the book), 1995; MS138.001.002.00081.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
      This is an excerpt from Dennett's Darwin's Dangerous Idea.
    - Es geht auch ohne Gott und Geist [German translation of excerpt from Darwin's Dangerous Idea], 1996; MS138.001.002.00081.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Our Vegetative Soul: The Search for a Reliable Model of the Human Self: A Review of Descartes' Error, by Antonio Damasio, 1995; MS138.001.002.00082; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Interview with Daniel C. Dennett, 1995 -- 1997; MS138.001.002.00083; Dennett, Daniel C.; Unknown
    - Interview with Daniel C. Dennett, 1995; MS138.001.002.00083.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    - Qualia, 1997; MS138.001.002.00083.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Interview with Daniel C. Dennett, 1995; MS138.001.002.00084; Dennett, Daniel C.; Kilheffer, Robert (Box 2)
  - La percezione èil 'bordo d'attacco' della memoria? [Italian translation of Is Perception the 'Leading Edge' of Memory?], 1995; MS138.001.002.00085; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - The Path Not Taken, 1995; MS138.001.002.00086; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - The Self and Its Consciousness: An Interview with Daniel C. Dennett, 1995; MS138.001.002.00087; Dennett, Daniel C.; Shakunle, Lere (Box 2)
  - Reply to Letters to the Editor, 1995; MS138.001.002.00088; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Also includes letters the editor, written in response to the excerpt of Darwin's Dangerous Idea.
  - Consciousness Revisted: An Interview with Daniel C. Dennett, 1995; MS138.001.002.00089; Dennett, Daniel C.; Flynn, Tom; Madigan, Tim (Box 2)
  - Foreword to The Subtlety of Sameness: A Theory and Computer Model of Analogy-Making, by Robert French, 1995; MS138.001.002.00090; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Animal Consciousness: What Matters and Why, 1995; MS138.001.002.00091; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Definitions of homunculus, intentionality, Mentalese, mentalism, and topic-neutral, 1995; MS138.001.002.00092; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Overworking the Hippocampus, 1995; MS138.001.002.00093; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Multiple Drafts: An Eternal Golden Braid?, 1995; MS138.001.002.00094; Dennett, Daniel C.; Kinsbourne, Marcel (Box 2)
  - The Unimagined Preposterousness of Zombies, 1995; MS138.001.002.00095; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Conciousness; Phenomenology; Introspection; Functionalism
  - Do Animals Have Beliefs?, 1995; MS138.001.002.00096; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Hofstadter's Quest: A Tale of Cognitive Pursuit, 1995; MS138.001.002.00097; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Phenomenology; Fluid Concepts; Creative analogies; Cognitive science; Analogy- Computer Simulation; Artificial intelligence; Hofstadter, Douglas R., 1945-
  - Daniel Dennett: How Skyhooks Hoist Only Their Own Petards, 1995; MS138.001.002.00098; Hardesty, Larry (Box 2)
  - How to Make Mistakes, 1995; MS138.001.002.00098.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Daniel Dennett over bewustzijn: Het brein als virtuele machine [Interview in Dutch], 1996; MS138.001.002.00099; Siemelink, Hes; Buying, Paul; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - In principe zijn wij onsterfelijk [Interview in Dutch], 1996; MS138.001.002.00100; Dennett, Daniel C.
    Placeholder record
  - Letter to the Editor: Dennett's Reply to Johnson, 1996; MS138.001.002.00101; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Seeing is Believing--Or Is It?, 1996; MS138.001.002.00102; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Facing Backwards on the Problem of Consciousness, 1996 -- 1999; MS138.001.002.00103
    - Facing Backwards on the Problem of Consciousness, 1996; MS138.001.002.00103.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
      Conciousness; Qualia; Neuroscience; Functionalism
    - Tagurpidi teadvuseprobleemi kallale, 1999; MS138.001.002.00103.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Quantum Incoherence: A Review of Evolving the Mind: On the Nature of Matter and the Origin of Consciousness, by A.G. Cairns-Smith, 1996; MS138.001.002.00104; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Conciousness; Physics- Philosophy; Cairns-Smith, A.G.
  - Producing Future by Telling Stories, 1996; MS138.001.002.00105; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    - The Robot's Dilemma Revisited: The frame problem in artificial intelligence, 1996; MS138.001.002.00105.00003; Ford, Kenneth M.; Pylyshyn, Zenon W. (Box data_value_missing_ca701fe8d78187953f592b0c499a65b9)
      book
  - Discovering Who We Can Be: Conversations and Enlightenment, 1996; MS138.001.002.00106; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Discovering Who We Can Be: Conversations and Enlightenment, 1996; MS138.001.002.00106.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    - Discovering Who We Can Be: Conversations and Enlightenment, 1996; MS138.001.002.00106.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    - We Need to Talk!, 1996; MS138.001.002.00106.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Review of Other Minds: Critical Essays, 1969-1994, by Thomas Nagel, 1996; MS138.001.002.00107; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Philsophy; Naturalism; Philosophy of mind; Ethics; Book Reviews; Nagel, Thomas, 1937-
  - Two Confusions, 1996; MS138.001.002.00108; Dennett, Daniel C.
  - Bewußtsein hat mehr mit Ruhm als mit Fernsehen zu tun [German translation of Consciousness: More like Fame than Television], 1996; MS138.001.002.00109; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Cow-sharks, Magnet, and Swampman, 1996; MS138.001.002.00110; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Metaphilosophy; Naturalism; Conceptual analysis; Metaphysics
  - Granny Versus Mother Nature--No Contest, 1996; MS138.001.002.00111; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Semantics; Intentionality; Teleosemantics; Evolutionary biology; Fodor, Jerry A.
  - Response to The Deniable Darwin, by David Berlinski, 1996; MS138.001.002.00112; Dennett, Daniel C.
    PLACEHOLDER
  - The Scope of Natural Selection, 1996; MS138.001.002.00113; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    This article was originally published in the Boston Review (http://www.bostonreview.net/). Permission has been granted to reproduce the piece on the Tufts Digital Library.
    Natural selection; Evolutionary biology; Adaptationism; Orr, H. Allen, 1960-
  - Response to Peter Gomes, 1996; MS138.001.002.00114; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Waar zit het Bewustzijn? [Dutch translation of Where is Consciousness?], 1997; MS138.001.002.00115; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - When Hal Kills, Who's to Blame? Computer Ethics, 1997; MS138.001.002.00116; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Discussion: In the Beginning, there was Darwin; Reply to Mulhauser, 1997; MS138.001.002.00117; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Darwin's Dangerous Idea (Daniel C. Dennett); Memetics; Algorithm; Physics- Philosophy; Cosmology; Mulhauser, Gregory R.
  - Appraising Grace: What Evolutionary Good is God?: Review of Creation of the Sacred: Tracks of Biology in Early Religions, by Walter Burkert, 1997; MS138.001.002.00118; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - Faith in Truth, 1997 -- 2001; MS138.001.002.00119; Dennett, Daniel C.
    - Faith in Truth, 1997; MS138.001.002.00119.00001; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
      This file contains Dennett's final draft of the speech, not in published form.
    - Fe na verdade [Portuguese translation of Faith in Truth, 1997; MS138.001.002.00119.00002; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    - Faith in the Truth, 1999; MS138.001.002.00119.00003; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    - To Tell the Truth?, 2001; MS138.001.002.00119.00004; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
      Postmodernism; Truth; Science; Religion; Multiculturalism
    - Faith in Truth, 2000; MS138.001.002.00119.00006; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
  - A Scientific Snow Job, 1997; MS138.001.002.00120; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Evolutionary biology; Natural selection; Adaptationism; Intelligent design; Dawkins, Richard, 1941
  - Interview with Daniel C. Dennett, 1997; MS138.001.002.00121; Dennett, Daniel C.; Springer, Michael (Box 2)
  - Darwinian Fundamentalism, 1997; MS138.001.002.00122; Gould, Stephen Jay (Box 2)
  - Evolution: The Pleasure of Pluralism, 1997; MS138.001.002.00123; Gould, Stephen Jay (Box 2)
  - Darwinian Fundamentalism: An Exchange, 1997; MS138.001.002.00124; Dennett, Daniel C. (Box 2)
    Natural selection; Punctuated equilibrium (evolution); Adaptationism; Darwin, Charles; Gould, Stephen Jay